<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://yuxinshen233.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://yuxinshen233.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-10-26T22:25:29+01:00</updated><id>https://yuxinshen233.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yuxin Shen</title><subtitle>Personal website of Yuxin Shen. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Turing Institute Interest Group seminar series</title><link href="https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/DCBTuring/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Turing Institute Interest Group seminar series"/><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/DCBTuring</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/DCBTuring/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="abstract">Abstract</h4> <p>I am co-organising a Turing Institute Interest Group seminar series on <a href="https://www.turing.ac.uk/research/interest-groups/data-centric-biological-design-and-engineering">Data-Centric Biological Design &amp; Engineering</a>. See the <a href="https://data-centric-biodesign-tig.github.io">website</a> for more information about schedules, speakers and the zoom link.</p> <h4 id="topics">Topics</h4> <p>Our work spans several focus areas within engineering biology and artificial intelligence. The following topics capture the main themes we explore in our sessions and discussions:</p> <h5 id="protein-design-and-genotype-phenotype-mapping">Protein Design and Genotype-Phenotype Mapping</h5> <p>This session explores the forefront of protein design and genotype-phenotype mapping. We focus on how computational models and machine learning techniques are being used to predict protein structures and functions from genetic information. The session will highlight innovative applications in drug discovery, synthetic biology, and personalized medicine, demonstrating the potential to design proteins with specific functions and to understand the genetic basis of phenotypic traits.</p> <h5 id="automation-of-biological-systems">Automation of Biological Systems</h5> <p>This session focuses on the automation of biological systems, showcasing the integration of robotics, artificial intelligence, and high-throughput screening technologies. We will discuss how these automated systems are transforming biological research by accelerating experimental processes, improving reproducibility, and enabling large-scale studies. Attendees will gain insights into the latest developments in laboratory automation and how these technologies are being utilized to streamline complex biological workflows, from sample preparation to data analysis.</p> <h5 id="physically-informed-biodesign">Physically-informed Biodesign</h5> <p>Physically-informed biodesign leverages principles from physics and engineering to create robust and efficient biological systems. This session delves into how physical models and simulations are used to inform the design and optimization of biological processes and materials. Topics include the application of biomechanics, fluid dynamics, and materials science to biodesign, providing a comprehensive overview of how interdisciplinary approaches are being used to solve complex biological problems and develop new biotechnologies.</p> <h5 id="genomics-and-microbial-engineering-with-big-data">Genomics and Microbial Engineering with Big Data</h5> <p>Our final session focuses on genomics and microbial engineering, emphasizing the role of big data in these fields. We will discuss how large-scale genomic data sets are being analyzed to uncover new insights into microbial functions, interactions, and ecosystems. This session covers the use of advanced data analytics, bioinformatics, and machine learning techniques in genomics research, demonstrating how these tools are driving discoveries in microbial engineering, biotechnology, and environmental microbiology.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="activities"/><category term="AI and Biology"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[co-organising a seminar series]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BOPE-GPT, Preference Exploration with the curious AI chemist</title><link href="https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/Bayesian_optimization_hackathon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BOPE-GPT, Preference Exploration with the curious AI chemist"/><published>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/Bayesian_optimization_hackathon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/Bayesian_optimization_hackathon/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="abstract">Abstract</h4> <p>For the Bayesian Optimization Hackathon for Chemistry and Materials (27-28 March 2024), our team finished and presented the project on BOPE-GPT, Preference Exploration with the curious AI chemist.</p> <p>Bayesian optimization with preference exploration (BOPE) is designed for Bayesian optimization of expensive-to-evaluate experiments, where the response surface function of the experiment generates vector-valued outcomes over which a decision-maker (DM) has preferences. In this project, we combined the BOPE pipeline with a language model, using the language model as the decision-maker. We worked on a multi-pbjective optimization problem (optimal production of the Fischer-Tropsch reaction) with this pipeline. Furthermore, we built an app for easy LLM-based BOPE.</p> <p>I mainly worked on the data preprocessing and Bayesian optimization pipeline (Single-objective BO, Multi-objective BO and BOPE) building.</p> <p>See <a href="https://ac-bo-hackathon.github.io/projects/project-16-bope-gpt/">project description</a> and our <a href="https://github.com/AC-BO-Hackathon/BOPE-GPT/tree/main">Git-hub page</a> for more details.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="activities"/><category term="Bayesian Optimization"/><category term="LLM"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bayesian Optimization Hackathon for Chemistry and Materials]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Impact of DNA representation on the sequence-to-expression models</title><link href="https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/EMBL/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Impact of DNA representation on the sequence-to-expression models"/><published>2024-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/EMBL</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yuxinshen233.github.io/blog/2024/EMBL/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="abstract">Abstract</h4> <p>I gave a flash talk and the poster presentation at EMBL Symposium: AI and Biology. The topic is on DNA mechanistic representation for sequence-to-expression modelling.</p> <p>See <a href="/assets/pdf/Flashtalk_EMBL.pdf">slides</a> and <a href="/assets/pdf/Poster_EMBL.pdf">poster</a> for more details.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="talks"/><category term="DNA representation"/><category term="mechanistic features"/><category term="Graph Neural Network"/><category term="feature stacking"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flash talk and poster at EMBL Symposium]]></summary></entry></feed>